Guide to the Albert Cohen Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Albert Cohen papers
circa 1970-2000
SC1062
Cohen, Albert, 1929-
2 Linear feet (2 boxes)
The materials consist primarily of research files from the French Académie de musique, as well as a few administrative files from his time as chair of the Music Dept.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
The materials were a gift of Albert Cohen, 2011.
Information about Access
Open for research.
Biographical/Historical note
Professor of Music Emeritus at Stanford, Albert Cohen is a distinguished musicologist and historian of music theory, specializing in French music of the 17th and 18th century. He was chair of the Music Department from 1973-1990, during which time he raised funds for, desiged and launched the Braun Music Center. A masterful performer on both violin and treble viol, Cohen is a graduate of Juilliard and former Guggenheim fellow and contributor to the New Grove Dictionary of Music and Musicians and Cambridge History of Western Music Theory. He retired from Stanford in 2001.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist primarily of research files from the French Académie de musique, as well as a few administrative files from his time as chair of the Music Dept.
Arrangement note
The materials are arranged in two series: Series 1. Administrative Files; Series 2. Research Files.
Access Terms
Cohen, Albert, 1929-; Music--France--History and criticism.; Music--France--Paris--Manuscripts; Music--Theory--17th century.; Music--Theory--18th century.; Stanford University--Faculty.
Collection Contents
- Administrative Files, Series 1
  - Personal Correspondence, 1973-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Stanford appointment, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Research Files, Series 2
  - Manuscript notes (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Collected documents, 1947-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Theatre (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Biographical files (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - C. Perrault (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript notes (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - -1695 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Savveur, 1969-1716 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1696-1699 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dodart, 1699-1707 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1700-1739 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1740-1759 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1760-1769 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1770-1779 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1780-1789 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1790- (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Musset-Rapport, 1774 Feb 9 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Other manuscript material, Thevenard-Dornel (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - AMS Paper (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Jean Marius, Dossier Marius, Archives of the Academy of Sciences (Paris) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 18th-century silk string photographs (Box 2, Folder 8)
- CV (Box 2, Folder 9)